## Ricardo Jorge Fernandes da Silva Carlos

M. 0751 5146 203
E. ricardo.carlos.uk@gmail.com
Flat 52, Salford House, Seyssel Street, E14 3HZ
https://ricardo-developer.github.io/

#### **Personal statement**

I am transitioning from the Airline Industry, where I worked for the past 6 years, to Web & Mobile Developer, I am looking to join a small team where I can learn, use my skills acquired and start as a junior developer. I'm challenging myself to always be up to date on the technological landscape with my self-learning ability.

In November 2016, I decided that I want to go for something more challenging than the work I was doing. I was always fascinated with programming and Mobile environments but never got around doing that. So, since then, I have been learning how to code and have gotten familiar with various parts of the Front end and Back end side of the development.

I finished a course of Web & Mobile developer, which includes HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript and the Framework Bootstrap; Multi-Platform Mobile Application Development using Cordova, Ionic, AngularJS; CMS of which Drupal and WordPress; Native Java

Development for Android, SEO / SEM and more recently I'm finishing to learn AngularJS with the Ionic Framework for mobile

development.

## **Key Skills**

- Proactive person who can work effectively under my influence and stressful conditions;
- Excellent communication skills, both written and verbal;
- Self-motivated, efficient with high attention to details;
- Problem-solving attitude and skills;
- Flexible in assignments;
- Good eye for design;
- Honest, dependable, reliable.

#### **Employment History**

## Web Developer / Support and Maintenance - Laminar (laminarmad.com)

(December 2019 – October 2019) Porto, Portugal

- Redesigning website using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Bootstrap, AngularJS and PHP;
- Improving performance and accessibility for different types of handheld devices;
- Lower the maintenance effort later on;
- Provide routine maintenance and support for all computers of the company;
- Conducted necessary upgrades to hardware and software as needed;
- · Maintained detailed and up to date inventory of all technological equipment;
- Utilized and repaired all common office equipment.

### **Airline Supervisor - Air Horizont**

#### (April 2018 – October 2018) Porto, Portugal

- Leading all aspects of the airline ground station;
- Monitor Handling operations services, coordinating flight operations/dispatch, crew members, sales and reservations, passenger, ramp, catering and other services;
- Act as the controller and manager of the assistance to Passengers in disruption situations such as delays, diversion's, cancellations, overbooking and others according to EU regulations;
- Establishing a customer-focused environment where the priority of each employee is excellent customer service;
- Measures the KPI's against the actual performance, reporting the results to Ground Operation's team every week.

## Sky Handling Partner - Flight and Traffic Coordinator, Load Planner, Operations Controller

#### (November 2014 – November 2016) London, UK

- Supervision, assistance with passenger services and passengers being directed to and from the aircraft safely;
- Weight and balance of aircraft, to include the loading instruction to ramp staff;
- Responsible for the safe co-ordination of the pushback/start-up procedure on departure of the aircraft;
- Responsible for the timely sending of all movement messages following the aircraft's departure;
- LUFTHANSA OPS Basic Aircraft Handling Ramp Narrow Body and LH Regional Aircraft Certificate, issued by Lufthansa at Seeheim on December 2015.

## Traffic Agent (Supervisor) - Air Transat / Swissport

#### (November 2010 – October 2014) Porto, Portugal

- Provide logistical coordination and services for FBO Corporate Aircraft, Charter, Military and Head of State Aircrafts;
- Ensuring that productivity and performance criteria are met in the designated areas of responsibility including fulfilling regular performance and quality assessment reports;
- Making recommendations on all aspects of company ground handling operations whilst seeking to identify
  opportunities and improve performance and productivity;
- Diary management, typing documents, making weekly/monthly reports;
- Managing incoming requests for Executive Flights/Private Aircraft Operations;
- Worked with corporate management to maximize operational performance in areas of on-time performance.

### **Education**

## Web & Mobile Developer - CESAE, Porto

(January 2017 – December 2017) Porto, Portugal

#### A-levels:

- Front End Web development HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery
- Back End Python, PHP, MySQL
- Multi-Platform Mobile Application Development Cordova, Ionic, Node.js, AngularJS
- Mobile Development Frameworks with Xamarin / C# using Visual Studio
- CMS Drupal, WordPress
- Mobile Native Language Java using Android Studio.

# **Tourism Degree - Instituto Superior Politécnico Gaya/Porto**

(September 2006 – November 2010) Porto, Portugal

Main Subjects:

- Marketing
- Tourism Legislation and regulations
- Preparation of Business Plans
- Management of Human Resources

## Wyższa Szkoła Hotelarstwa i Gastronomii w Poznaniu/Poznan - Erasmus

(September 2009 – July 2010) Poznan, Poland

Main Subjects:

- Management
- Tourist Market Analysis
- Tourism Consultancy
- Economics of Tourism and Recreation

## **Interests**

Aviation enthusiast, fitness and health and Web & Mobile programming.

# Language

Native Portuguese, fluent in English and Spanish.